

- **J** +20 109 699 3853
- www.johnydesigns.com
- Cairo, Egypt.

COVER LETTER

DEAR SIR / MADAM,

My name is John, I am a Sr. System Administrator offering over 8 years of experience, an expert in Windows OS, MAC OSX & Linux, with a strong development background.

My target title is DevOps Engineer, currently I am focusing to master Python, REST, Flask, Docker, MySQL, Jenkins and AWS.

My previous roles in the IT field was providing level 1, level 2 and level 3 technical support, troubleshooting, and maintenance of the technology infrastructure and systems for endpoint device management Including win-servers (2003, 2008, 2012), Mac server, firewall Linux server, Render Farm, network management, NAS, SAN, LAN, WAN, RAID, ticketing systems, software distribution, updates, patching virus protection, and imaging.

Besides my main experience in the IT field, I have been using Adobe Products for the past 12 years and Front-End for the past 5 years, I am not a Graphic Designer but I have a quite good taste and freelance experience doing websites, logos, mobile apps, leaflets & retouch, you are welcome to check my website johnydesigns.com.

I have enclosed my cover letter for your review. I appreciate your time.

Sincerely,

John Bedeir Sr. System Administrator



) +20 109 699 3853

www.johnydesigns.com

Cairo, Egypt.

Summary

I am a Sr. System Administrator offering over 8 years of experience, an expert in Linux, Windows OS & MAC OSX with a strong development background.

Plus a quite good experience in Web Design.

Career Objective

Currently, I am focusing to gain more experience in Python, Containers & Cloud Services and my aim title is DevOps Engineer.

Sr. System Admin

Linux Sys Admin

DevOps

Python

Automation

Work Experiences

Jan 2020 - Current

IT QoS & USER EXPERIENCE ANALYST

Orange Business Services

Cairo, Egypt

Orange is a French multinational telecommunication corporation.

- · IT Helpdesk Audit & Quality of service
- · Working on enhancing the user experience.
- UI & UX using: Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, and XD.
- · Working in AGILE.
- Front-End Development Tools: VS Code, WAMP, Git, GitLab.
- · In charge of designing communications within OBS.
- Creating a promo video for IT Community Space using After Effects.
- **Project 1** SDMP: Making it responsive using Bootstrap & CSS3
- Project 2 Survey Bot: Building a website from scratch following
 Orange branding guidelines using XD & Front-End Development.

Sep 2018 - Sep 2019

IT PROJECT MANAGER

Yaryor Technologies

Dubai, UAE

YARYOR is a small company, mostly working on projects that include new technologies like Robotics, Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Digital Signage, Web Development, and Mobile applications.

- IT Manager
- Application Testing (VR, AR, Android & iOS)
- Managing Host, domains and email server using cPanel
- · Task Management: Bitrix24, Wunderlist, JIRA, Trello
- · Front-End, CMS & Adobe XD
- Daily Report and Weekly meeting.

Mar 2016 - Apr 2018

SENIOR IT SPECIALIST

Plus500 BG

Sofia, Bulgaria

Plus 500 is a huge international firm providing online trading, working there was a great opportunity I started there with the Technical Support team then I got promoted to Senior IT providing High-level Support for Windows OS in two offices.

- Provide 24/7 Level 2 Support across all facilities.
- Ensure that helpdesk tickets are closed or escalated promptly.
- Ensure there are no alerts in the Symantec endpoint console.
- Monitoring the Server room temperature via sensor.
- Performs other related duties as assigned.

Expertise

Linux, Windows & MAC

Bash Scripting

Vmware, Parallels & Virtualbox

Web Hosting: cPanel

Adobe Photoshop

Hardware replacement

Network Installation & troubleshooting

NIC Teaming / Renderfarm

HTML5 / CSS3

Languages

Arabic	Native
English	Fluent
Bulgarian	A1

Work Experiences

Jan 2014 - Jul 2015 SENIOR IT SPECIALIST

Aroma Studios



AROMA is an extraordinary company for media production in the middle east, I got the opportunity for working as a Senior IT with a team of IT providing 24/7 coverage with level 2 crossover platform support Windows OS, Mac OSX, and Linux.

- Level 1 2 Support for all instance (on location, via phone & remotely)
- Install and configure linux and perform system maintenance.
- Ensure pending tasks have been solved.
- Check Kaspersky endpoint security management console and ensure there are no alerts.
- Check the Servers & Renderfarm room temperature.
- · Performs other related duties as assigned

Sep 2011 - Dec 2013 IT SPECIALIST / FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Arabcomed



The Arab Company for Medical Products is a factory for manufacturing pharmaceutical this was my first full-time job after graduation providing level 1 help desk support and Create new designs and editing the company website.

- · Level 1 Support on location, via phone or remotely,
- Create New Designs for the next coming product
- Ensure all the endpoint devices are working properly.
- Check the Server room temperature.



Education and Certificates

2015 - 2019

Masters in Computer Science and Engineering

Technical University, Sofia, Bulgaria.

2007 - 2011

Bachelors in Computer Science

Future Academy, Cairo, Egypt.

Volunteering Activity

Member of IT Committee

Enactus Organization, Cairo, Egypt.

CERTIFICATES & SELF-STUDIES

MySQL	(Self-Study)
Python	(Self-Study)
Docker	(Self-Study)
Git	(Self-Study)
RHCSA	(Self-Study)
LPIC-1	(Self-Study)
Bash Scripting	(Self-Study)
Adobe XD	(Self-Study)
HTML/ CSS3	(Self-Study)
MCSA	(Self-Study)
Adobe Photoshop	(Certified)
ICDL	(Certified)

OTHER SKILLS & **APPS**

Ubuntu, Mint & CentOs

VS Code, Spyder, Atom & **Brackets**

Grsync, Timeshift

Synaptic, GDebi

Untangle network security

<u>Dameware</u>, Radmin & PDQ Deploy

WDS & NetInstall

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe InDesigns

Adobe After Effects



